# JOSE RAMON PRIETO DEL PRADO

### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Software Engineer**

**UST Global** 

August 2022 - Actual

- Implementation and maintenance of JAVA application that receives a significant
  amount of data traffic through MQ queues and web services, so it is necessary to
  implement a code as efficient as possible, with many unit, integration and system
  tests.
- Collaborate developing util scripts with BASH for daily tasks like list all SSH tunels, all
  docker containers with fzf and connect to them by selecting them.
- Convince and bring my knowledge about the importance of SOLID principles, hexagonal architecture and many of the DDD techniques in short for the type of project we are working on, since it is a complex project, and a code easier to see, organized and more adapted to a possible change, would give the possibility to migrate to new technologies that in our case benefit us in a much simpler way.

#### Junior Software Engineer

**Stratesys** 

February 2022 - August 2022

- Implementation and maintenance of APIs and microservices with Spring Boot.
   Developing and thinking models for new projects and implementing them from scratch with JPA.
- Set up a keycloack server with Docker which is an identity manager for each of the clients we had.
- Solve concurrency problems in the execution of the GitHub Actions pipeline of one of
  the projects. It was the case that two team members made a pull request or a push at
  the same time and 2 parallel piplines were executed and could give conflicts when
  the oldest pipeline is the one that makes the last deployment, so I solved it by
  stopping the execution whenever a new one arrives, so that the latter is the one that is
  executed.

#### **Full Stack Software Developer**

**Pixelware** 

March 2018 - September 2018

- Implementation of new endpoints for the APIs of our projects with Spring. Adding new functionality to the model of some of our projects using JPA.
- Spring Framework learning challenge

# PROJECTS AND ABILITIES

- FinanzYou. Financial application that allows you to manage your portfolio, where you can see a complete overview of your portfolio. The application consists of two parts, including the backend, which serves me among other things to know what stocks each user has in their portfolio, the technology used was Java simply for ease and being the tool I know best and it was a university project. I also used Spring Boot as a framework because it makes it very easy to implement APIs with Java. The other part would be the frontend, which is about connecting to other APIs to get the value of each Stock and do all the corresponding portfolio calculations among other things. For the web part I used Vue JS as experimentation, with which I learned how to build a web using reusable components with this framework. Application available at <a href="mailto:finanzyoufront.herokuapp.com">finanzyoufront.herokuapp.com</a> and source code available at <a href="mailto:github.com/jprieto96/finanz-you-frontend">github.com/jprieto96/finanz-you-frontend</a> and <a href="mailto:github.com/jprieto96/finanz-you-backend">github.com/jprieto96/finanz-you-backend</a>
- MySeries. Android application for the management of series, movies and TV shows. It consists of the frontend part, where the application is modeled, and the most interesting part, which is the backend, which accesses the resource layer to know which user saves which movie, series, etc. among other things. The novelty of this application is its push notification system implemented with firebase, which works as a queue and every time an event is generated a custom notification is sent to the user. The backend was implemented with Kotlin as experimentation, to test coroutines, etc... Source code availabe at <a href="mailto:gitlab.com/jprieto96/myseries">gitlab.com/jprieto96/myseries</a>
- Portfolio of the rest of smaller projects I'm doing in my GitHub like minigames or miniprojects, exercises about data structures, trying and testing other programming languages, new frameworks, libraries, etc...- github.com/jprietog6

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

in <u>linkedin.com/in/jose-ramon-prieto-del-prado</u>

joseprieto9657@gmail.com

+34 682898814

github.com/jprieto96

# PERSONAL PROFILE

Software engineer with 1+ year of experience working mainly in the implementation and maintenance of backend microservices, always bringing my ability to select which architecture is appropriate to apply and which design patterns are suitable for each project depending on the maintainability and scalability that you want to give. Although Java and Spring Boot are the stack I have the most experience in, the technology is not the important thing, as it is the easiest part to learn, so most of my time is spent analysing and detecting problems, looking for a good solution and a good technique to solve it.

# **EDUCATION HISTORY**



Software Engineering Universidad Complutense de Madrid 2018-2022

Average Mark: **8.28**/10. Honors Degree obtained in Data Structures (2020) and Advanced Databases (2021)



Computer Science University of Hertfordshire 2021-2022

Exchange student for one semester through the Erasmus 21/22 program



https://jprieto96.github.io/cv/